# Sweta Rani Patra

# Professional Summary

Technology Professional with 4+ years of experience in software development, testing, automation, and project management. Expertise in development of applications using Java, JavaScript, Node.js, Express JS, React, NextJS, PHP, SQL Server, MongoDB, Dynamo DB, HTML5 and CSS3. Excellent knowledge of Agile and Scrum development environment. Possess decent communication, interpersonal, learning and organizing skills.

## Work Experience

Openscreen Inc. Jan 2023 - Current

Software Developer Intern

- Developing a single-page web-application in Openscreen Platform using Node.js, React, NextJS and Typescript.
- Developing a REST API using AWS cloud services including API Gateway, Lambda functions, JavaScript, DynamoDB, S3 storage, and Openscreen's SDK and API.
- Design and validation of the REST API endpoints, server-side and business logic using Postman and Dry-Dock scripts.
- Using agile methodology for design and development of the project.

Accenture Pvt Ltd. Oct 2017 - Dec 2021

Application Development Senior Analyst

- Developed and enhanced web-based softwares using C, jQuery, Azure, Web API, JavaScript, Angular 6, MSSQL, HTML5, CSS3, and Bootstrap 3.
- Monitored data transition from SAP HANA to Azure Cosmos and Mongo DB using DATADOG.
- Worked with OpenShift and Kubernetes for automating application deployment, scaling, and operations.
- Translated stakeholder requirements into over 10 different tangible deliverables such as functional specifications, user cases, user stories, workflow/process diagrams, data flow/data model diagrams.
- Continuously involved in Automation of the Regression Suite (after every Release) for Application using UFT (11.5 to 12.00 versions).
- Used Postman to test the RESTFUL API for HTTP requests.
- Expert in working with multiple teams via triage calls and resolving production issues as quickly as possible.

## Projects

#### Movies App (JavaScript, NodeJS, Express JS, Express handlebars, Mongoose, MongoDB)

- Developed an Express JS application to extract, add, update and delete movies data from MongoDB collections.
- Designed the schema for structuring the collection using Mongoose.
- Allowed users to interact with the data through user-friendly interface developed using Express Handlebars Template Engine and Bootstrap.
- Used JSON Web Tokens (JWT) to secure the API and Berypt library to encrypt user credentials.
- Deployed the app to Cyclic, a serverless cloud infrastructure.

## Customer Management Application (Java, JDBC, Java Swing, Oracle Database)

- Used Java Swing to develop a user-friendly application interface.
- Utilized JDBC to retrieve the data from the database.
- Performed various operations like adding, storing, and customizing customer details on the data stored in the Oracle Database.

#### Book Management App (JSP, Servlet, HTML, CSS, MySQL)

- Created an intuitive application using JSP, HTML, and CSS for the front-end.
- Used Servlets to implement the business logic and presentation logic.
- Additionally, the application performed various CRUD operations on book details stored in a MySQL database, such as adding, storing, and deleting records.

# CERTIFICATIONS

- Agile Professional Certification
- AZ-900 Microsoft Azure Fundamentals
- AZ-204 Developing Solutions for Microsoft Azure
- AZ-303 Microsoft Azure Architect Technologies
- AZ-304 Microsoft Azure Architect Technologies

## SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, C, PHP, HTML, JavaScript, Typescript, XML, Python, Scala, Shell

Scripting

Software: NetBeans, Tomcat, JBoss, IntelliJ IDEA, SQL Server Management Studio,

Azure DevOps, Hadoop MapReduce, HIVE, HBase, Flume, Pig, Jira, GitHub,

Red Hat OpenShift, Datadog, Jenkins, Confluence, TFS, Tableau

Operating Systems: Windows 7/8/XP, Linux, Mac iOS, Android

Database: MySQL, Oracle, MS SQL Server, Azure Cosmos DB, PostgreSQL, Mongo

DB, Redis, SQLite, Dynamo DB

Web Technology: HTML5, CSS3, Java Script, XML, J2EE(Servlets), J2EE servers, Angular 6,

Node.js, React.js, NextJS

Testing: Selenium with Java, Cucumber, BDD, UFT, JUnit, Dry-dock

## EDUCATION

2021 - present Postgraduate(Information Technology Solutions) at **Humber College** (GPA: 9.1/10)

Dean's List

2013 - 2017 Bachelor's Degree at **Odisha University of Technology** (GPA: 8.0/10)